[Music]
hello and welcome to this business
Central launch events session today
we're going to talk to you about how you
can create customer Centric onboarding
experiences my name is CERN and I'm a
product manager in the business Central
engineering team I'm here today with
Sarah who is a ux designer in our Design
Studio let's start by Framing the
problem the problem is customers love
business Central so do we and so do you
well is that a problem well it kind of
is a problem because there are so many
customers who would like to go to
business Central that they're queuing up
outside our door outside your door in
such a way that you struggle with
serving them all and that's a risk
because the risk is one they will find
another partner or even worse they will
find another product so we need to
figure out a way to scale the channel
even more there are simply not enough
human resources to go around luckily we
have tools in the toolbox that can help
us all and you to do just
that before we go there let's start by
looking looking at the onboarding vision
that we have the vision is simply that
any customer can find explore and start
using business Central plus add-on apps
by
themselves now notice the emphasis on
start using it doesn't mean that all
companies will become 100% proficient
without any
assistance and by themselves doesn't
mean Without Partners but it means that
maybe there's an Unity to rethink how
you as a partner are involved in the
process what can you do with less
handson and more digital
guidance to help us execute towards that
Vision we see at least four things uh
being necessary one of them is it's
super important that we match and
Prospects and customers are matched with
Partners the right partners and the
right solutions from day one so that
their very first meeting with the
product is as great as it can
be next is our onboarding philosophy is
not to drag all users through all setup
now it is to template as much as
possible and then let users selfs serve
and self- finalize the rest of the
experience that can be an evaluation
experience in a trial but it could also
be in a live setting where they need to
set up the system ready for productive
use
and to that end we'd like you to think
about how you can take the knowledge of
your consultants and pack it into some
IP into some apps for app Source now you
have domain knowledge and you have
things that you do over and over again
and that work that you do over and over
again are great candidates for being
packaged into some digital guidance
asking the customer questions inside the
product leading to some onboarding
scenarios where your Consultants can
then move on and instead serve I'd say
more complex problems more complex
scenarios and help customers that have
those needs instead of focusing and
spending time on all the
basics finally it's super important that
any user can learn while doing inside
the product a user needs to be able to
intuitively understand what's a feature
about why does the page exist what's the
next logical step of course there are
some complex scenarios out there that a
consultant will need to guide the user
but think about how you can support that
kind of Learning
Journey so to
summarize there's a huge opportunity out
there there are so many customers that
wants to go to BC that's also a risk so
make sure that you're set up to handle
that risk now scale is critical we
simply need to scale more and you can
scale more with the same resources if
you invest in these onboarding
capabilities and how you do that is
driven by Automation and that's what
this session is all
about so enough with the business
motivations for investing into
onboarding let's talk about The Human
Side the more emotional side of
onboarding to a new service or to a new
thing so Sarah I wondered can you talk
to us about what does it mean to on
board to something new and how have we
brought that philosophy into business
Central yes I can thank you
s here you see someone entering a hotel
in a new city where he has never been
before so he's a little uncertain if
he's at the right
place but hopefully he will get a warm
and personal welcome and he will feel
expected and comfortable finding his way
around and getting the most out of his
stay trying out a new product for the
first time can be a bit similar you can
be a little uncertain if you're at the
right
place and maybe even a bit overwhelmed
by all the information so having a clear
indication of where to start and being
able to find your way around is really
important for a good first
experience
and what we found in our studies is that
while some users like to go and explore
on their own right away others might
need a little more handholding along the
way so when designing the onboarding
framework for business Central it was
crucial for us to really cater for both
of these two types of users ensuring we
didn't block the path to anyone yet
still making sure that we had relevant
in context uh guidance along the way to
getting productive with business Central
today you will hear more about how you
as a partner can scale this onboarding
experience to even more
customers while still ensuring relevant
onboarding content to your customers
business needs but first s is going to
tell us a little bit more about the
partner and customer Journey definitely
thank you so much Sarah so you touched
on something important there which is
relevant content and today what you know
as the standard trial experience that
you start on dynamics.com doesn't really
give you relevant content well not as
relevant as it could be because it's a
generic trial you started on the
dynamics.com website you venture into
the Kronos evaluation company maybe you
Venter into the non-evaluation company
called my company and then at some point
we hope you'll contact the Microsoft
partner buy your license or get started
somehow with business Central that's the
most well Journey for those who just
Venture into into this on their own and
find our website the other scenario you
know the other Journey that you know is
when when a prospect meets your website
maybe they saw your solution they like
to see a like to get a demo or see that
solution in a trial there's a lot more
friction in that scenario because you
need to First establish the CSP
relationship that uh virtual paperwork
that needs to happen where you add the
trial skew to the customer and partner
Center Center you load up BC for them
you load any apps you think are relevant
for your for for that experience and you
load the configuration that you hand
over that experience to the prospect to
the customer and then at some point
hopefully they will continue that
Journey now we can remove the friction
in that while still providing that same
relevance for for the Prospect and this
is relatively new but there's a way to
create a digital experience that is has
your Special Sauce in it and now we're
going to show you what that's all about
basically on a timeline it could look
like this it ends with the customer
going live of course but it starts with
you profiling the prospect on your
website because to be able to give the
most relevant experience you need to
know something about that potential
customer like for example what industry
are they in what kind of business are
they running uh maybe what kind of
system are they currently using are they
using Excel or some other competitive
product product now that's all relevant
because you want to stage business
Central as being the great new solution
for them so you need to know about what
environment are they operating in right
now so after you profile them you
redirect them to the signup um at
dynamics.com so basically we spin up the
standard trial and we load an appsource
app that you have decided which one is
the most relevant one and the most
important thing is here that whatever
the outcome of the profiler was on your
website is carried through that journey
and is actually available in business
Central so you can pivot The Experience
based on the preferences the
expectations from that
customer that means that coming back to
the first pillar of our strategy you saw
that being able to be matched with the
partner solution from day Zero is
actually what's taking place here it's a
partner-driven experience at the very
first first sign in at the very first
meeting with the product that means to
Sarah's point that you know who wants to
go to the pool and who wants to go
straight to the bar and you can serve
them with what they
want so you can build an experience
where the prospect can try out in corus
you can even build in an embedded buying
experience that will take care of the
CSP uh part of things and take them
through uh the onboarding piece as well
in their own company and dynamically
load all the data that this customer
needs in terms of chart of accounts and
posting groups and what have you and
then the customer can go live and your
Consultants can then uh focus on the
more complex part of that of that
business to show this in a more
schematic way what happens is you have
your questionnaire on your website the
prospects fills in the answers depending
on what kind of questions it you ask
them they click a button they're
redirected to the standard trial signup
at Dynamic
mi.com we then spin up the standard
trial and then we add the app that you
have told us to add we then store the
information from the questionnaire the
answers in a system table inside
business Central and you can use those
before the sign in happens to Pivot add
more things to the experience based on
what those answers are this is a really
great way to make it customer
Centric so end of the day from the user
perspective what they see they sign up
and they see an experience they don't
see that anything else has been added
they just see it as one coherent
experience that has your special Source
in it so here you see a website this is
my partner website actually this is just
a power app that I quickly made to show
this but it will PR simple a website so
here I want to ask new prospects that
find my website some questions because I
want to give them the right experience
from from day one so I asked them about
what they're interested in doing with
business Central I asked them about what
system they're currently using and I
asked them about their company size how
many do you think will be using business
Central and in this case uh the the
prospect selects uh they are interested
in biodiversity and luckily we have a
solution just for that for tracking uh
biodiversity progress they also said
that they're interested in Excel or that
they come from Excel sorry uh they're
used to working with Excel and there are
10 to 25 users that use business Central
so we can see why that they've grown out
of using that um Excel spreadsheet now
what happens here when they start the
trial is that I need to construct the
right information to pass along to
business Central in order for business
Central to spin out the right uh the
right
solution it means that the combination
of these choices imply a collection of
onboarding elements checklist tasks
Banner rooll Center what have you in a
coherent experience that that's bundled
together in an appsource app and I want
to load that app so when they have
chosen these specific things I might
want to load my solution a but had they
chosen for example these three things I
want a load solution B and so on and you
will be the one who can decide for your
company which Solutions do we want to
load so I click the start trial Button
as a prospect I I'm directed to the
normal sign up process while I sign in
to my tenant or sign up to a new tenant
and then the important part here is that
all of that context where you came from
the outcome of the questionnaire is
passed along to business Central in this
case so now we load business Central we
create the environment with the standard
trial on top but we add your special
sauce we add your appsource app and its
dependencies and now now is the point
where your app is ready to say oh they
chose Excel as the previous system that
they come from hey I might want to load
a checklist item that describes why BC
is great for uh Excel users that kind of
thinking so let's see how that plays out
so let's actually go and see see that
app I landed in business Central after
going through the signup and asking or
answering some some questions and I
already see a product here that is much
more relevant than the standard trial
I see that it has my name on it so I
feel welcome I also see that it's loaded
with an app called biodiversity
management so already now this just
speaks my language it speaks to my
expectations so and I see there's a
clear call to action here I'm I landed
here in an evaluation company and what
what we're about to show you here are
some examples of what you can do in
terms of onboarding so we're going to
talk through some of the onboarding
elements in this checklist this
checklist is not intended to be the
great checklist for you to onboard a
customer but it's intended to give you
inspiration to what kind of elements can
you use here so first of all use video
in this case I know that this Prospect
was interested in biodiversity so I want
to play them a video that will tell them
maybe a snack-sized video that will tell
them exactly why BC plus this
biodiversity management app is just
fantastic for the business let's assume
that we watched that video for now we
just we skipped
this maybe I also want to guide them
through setup and for some kinds of
modules for some kind of solutions the
checklist itself is not you know really
geared to handle many setup elements we
should really strive to have a fairly
short checklist so what we can do is
actually we can spin off we can Branch
off the checklist and run let's say a
sub checklist here so what you saw saw
me doing here was actually call the
assisted setup list page but it's
filtered now only to contain my setup
elements and that's a great way to say
hey here just a number of steps you need
to go through to have this module set up
in this case I just want to show you an
example of calling one of these so here
I have an assisted setup that says for
this biodiversity solution I need to
import some plants so now it's plants it
could be the chart of accounts it could
be posting groups it could be whatever
you want Import in terms of data as an
alternative to using configuration
packages so in this case and you can see
I've even branded this assisted setup I
want to import a list of plants from
GitHub so I know that I have a Json file
with plants that are open source on
GitHub because I want the community to
contribute to this list of
plants I click next and now we see it's
actually now listed in sort of a
temporary state so when I click next
they will actually be imported this is
just the way way for me to sort of
validate that it looks fine I this is
this is the list that I expect to to
import so we'll do that and we'll click
finish so you see how using an assistant
setup where I could even ask more
questions here to clarify which data do
I want to load so you can imagine if a
customer is not using uh doing projects
for example just leave those accounts
out of the chart of accounts or
something else where you don't want to
load data that is not used so think
about loading data in a just in time
fashion this way so let's just close
this one and say that we we did this
kind of setup for
now now the user also said we use Excel
today I want to speak to that because we
have some very cool Excel Integrations
so what I want to do is I want to open a
page on that plant data that I just
imported and I want to show a great
Spotlight tour that that's Spotlight the
Excel integration capabilities so I call
the spotlight tour here I can you as a
partner can modify this text of course
and say why is this great on this entity
to use uh edit in Excel so I call out
Excel here and say hey for example you
can edit this list of plans in Excel and
import it back into BC we're not going
to do that right now but this is just a
great way to call out these standard
Integrations like share to teams and
edit in
Excel let me go back here to to the
checklist now we also added new things
in this release so if I start now and
this actually is a report that I'm
starting I wanted to provide a super
cool report out of the box that is based
on Excel layouts I want them to see a
nice graph of all the plants they just
imported the new thing here is you see
the teating tip popping up for the
request page for the report request page
educating me about what can I expect
from this report why does it exist uh
maybe there could be some hints about
how to best filter it to get the best
exp experience with this report but in
this case I just want to see that nice
looking report and what we'll see it it
will open in in Excel and it shows me
already the plant occurrences last year
so remember we're tracking biodiversity
I want to keep track of how often has
this been reported as been spotted in
the wild so I can see here my list of
plants this is an Excel layout that I
provide with my app so the customer
hasn't even you know needed to anything
they don't need to do this when we print
this Excel layout uh or print this
report we will update the data set and
the graph will automatically update it's
super cool way to do alternative reports
for your for your customers and you can
imagine all kinds of uh complex or less
complex Excel layouts let's mark that as
complete as well now I can also of
course manage my plants so I can start
that list of plants I as I had before
and one extra cool thing that we added
in this release you already know the
teaing tips you know that you can add
markdown uh to do bold and italics
inside teaching tips and we can also
link so here we link to the insects page
we haven't tracked any insects yet but I
want to take the tour and here it says I
can analyze my top plants and basically
what this does it opens a query in
analysis mode saying that hey here's
some great data for you and now we have
a teaching that educates the user about
what is this analysis all about what is
it that you're seeing here because now
this is fairly simple and I can see that
it's sorted by number of occurrences but
it could be a more complex thing so it
could be great that I would be educated
about this and of course in this release
as I'm sure you will see uh now you can
for example duplicate it you give it
another name uh let me just call it test
and you can copy a link to this specific
analysis and send this to a colleague
send it in teams and when they open it
they will go directly into this analysis
because youve just spent a weekend doing
it and uh it's just a perfect analysis
so use teaching tips to educate users
about what are they seeing here all
right let's go back here and let's
actually go back to the
checklist
so let's skip this for
now finally in my example here I
actually want the user to go to my
website because we have the perfect
place for them to land after theyve gone
through this experience where we can
take them a step further but you could
also Imagine you could take them into my
company start setting things up for Real
uh add the data add more videos that
gist them through processes and then go
live so this was just one way to sort of
stitch together some onboarding pieces
you get the idea with all these elements
it's up to you to think about how you
can stitch them together together now
the great thing about what you just saw
here is that this app that I loaded here
is available on GitHub is the onboarding
sample app and you can go Fork it today
and use that as a template to hit the
ground running for your onboarding
experiences so that you will know which
events do you have to subscribe to where
do you do this and where do you do that
let's just go through the most important
ones now so what was actually customer
Centric to this experience that you just
saw well first of all we loaded a custom
R Center there's a few things that's
important for doing that so we loaded a
custom R Center we attached it to a role
and we set that role for the current
user uh before they signed in so you see
here the events that that are necessary
to subscribe to to make that happen you
can also see that in the um in the code
of the sample app we also changed the
welcome Banner texts and again to
Sarah's point before it's just super
important to greet them with the most
relevant uh text and greeting once you
see the product it literally is the
first thing that you see and you see
here which event you need to subscribe
to to do
that and speaking about relevance it's
really is the checklist tasks that are
uh you know doing the work this is your
stage to lead the customer through uh
that first experience what is it you
think they should get excited about this
is where you can do even pre-sale stuff
if they spin up uh spin up a new trial
you can use this for of course for the
real onboarding scenario as well and you
can do both that really is up to
you Branch off check list to do more
elaborate setups you saw me uh opening
the assisted setup list filtered to your
custom category and you do that by
calling the open assisted setup function
in the guide experience
item
and what we talked about before about
using assisted setups to ask more
questions to clarify which data do you
have to load here in my example I just
loaded the plants it could be that I
wanted to ask the user about hey are you
interested in trees or flowers only and
then only load that data you get the
idea for your data consider open
sourcing that data if you have data that
you build but many others also build
would it make sense to pull your
resources and and open source it could
be GitHub is a great source for those
kind of
things again call out the spotlight
tours shine a big bright Spotlight on
those core Integrations Excel and teams
for your custom entities it's a great
way to generate some excitement and one
of the reasons we hear customers
investing in business Central is the
whole ecosystem of surrounding apps from
Microsoft educate users with teaching
tips on reports it's a it's a great way
to give them some hints about what this
this report all about why should they
care about it and how should they maybe
uh set some initial filters to get the
best outcome and with other like with
other teaching tips you can use the
about title and about text properties to
do that in
Al again use Excel layouts you can do
stunning layouts and provide the Excel
layout file out of the box with your app
so the customer doesn't have to do
anything except but print the
report there's a great examples and
there more guidance at this aka.ms BC
EXL samples link check out the guidance
there for more samples and some TP tips
and
tricks and the final thing I want to
call out here is use teaching tips on
query objects as well it's it's a good
experience to get some guidance on hey
what is this analysis that I just just
opened directly from another page what
is it all
about so I talked a lot about these
different onboarding elements now I'd
like to learn more about some of the
guidance and best practices that I
should think about and you should think
about when you go and build these
onboarding experiences so Sarah can you
take us through that I would love to do
that so now we have established that
when the users arve at the role Center
in business Central the banner is there
to greet them and to really um be this
entrance um for where to get
started so when creating content for the
banner keep in mind to keep the welcome
message short and clear and to make the
user really discover and want to follow
that call to
action and once the user clicks the
action in this case show demo tours the
checklist shows up in the banner
providing overview and structure of the
relevant activities guiding the users
successfully through discovering key
values in business
Central so as s said the checklist is
really the main onboarding piece that
allows you to surface the different
onboarding components and orchestrate
what the customer goes through but just
remember that the user can move and
navigate freely between the tasks and
might even skip some of them to revisit
them later so you can't always guarantee
that they follow the order that you
decided and also consider the difference
between a checklist for the aval trial
situation where um you want the you you
want the users to experience the um
value propositions and the go to live
checklist where the purpose is to get
business Central set up in the perfect
way for the
customer so when putting together the
checklist for the evaluation and trial
keep in mind that the customer's
patience and maybe even time is really
short that's why we also have the little
minute indicator on every task so you
want to put together the checklist for
evaluation that is really short and with
as little friction as possible so it's
important um to try to avoid complex
tasks to not to for the users to not
feel
stuck May maybe start with a smaller
task first that gives them an
understanding of business Central as
well as a feeling of success and
progression in the checklist because we
know that that builds confidence in
users to um go and explore
further and also consider if you can use
a good mix of content as turn said so
not have all videos or all Spotlight
tools but a good mix uh creates a more
engaging
experience now the checklist used for go
live has a slightly different
goal now it's actually about setting
business Central and the user up for
doing work and the checklist items can
be a little more involved related to
setting up users
permissions and so on and in that case
it's really important that you consider
the user's role and make the che
checklist role
oriented so um if a user isn't
responsible for permissions showing a
task about permissions would not be a
good choice also keep setup as short as
possible preconfig as much as much as
you
can um what we have found also is that
if you have two many checklist items um
it doesn't work so well the checklist is
designed for five six maybe seven and if
you have more than that you can wrap
those up in an assisted setup list as s
showed and and guide the users that
way so as s showed Spotlight tours are a
really powerful way of showing some of
the key selling points in business
Central such as teams and Excel and the
superpower of this pattern is really um
that it allows users not only to
Discover it but actually go and try it
out with just two steps and hopefully
get wowed at the moment Spotlight tours
are all about teams and Excel what is up
to you to decide is on which Pages you
want to call out that particular
feature in case it's relevant on the
page Pages you have
built you can use the introduction text
on the first step to explain the value
it brings on that particular
page and remember when you're at a new
place it's sometimes a little difficult
to know where you are so give a little
hand there and introduce where you are
the Second Step it's all about it's it's
about pointing uh to that action where
the user can go and try it
out once users get more hands on with
the UI and they try out the scenarios on
their own teaching tips are valuable
method for educating users about what
they can do in a particular page again
when creating content for these be brief
make sure the user understands the key
value of the page as if you would
introduce it in one sentence to a
customer why is this page so great and
not how to use it if users want to learn
more make sure they can find relevant
documentation about your page in help
instead now if you want users to
discover key elements on a page the tour
with teaching tips are a better choice
because they can point to a particular
action or field and provide an
explanation but remember you can't use
teaching tips to prescribe a certain
business process the sequence of the
teaching tips is controlled by the order
they appear on the page top to button
which makes sense
because users view pages from top to
bottom and you should already have
arranged your fields in terms of
priority uh from top to
bottom and again sh shorter and fewer
tips is usually better if you try to
communicate too much in these inui
elements you might not get the result
that you intended the users will
typically get tired of balloons and
teaching tips and maybe skip it all
together so narrow it down and think
about the three most important things us
just really need to discover and
understand and then use the tool tips
for the other
explanations so as mentioned in the
beginning one of our main goals with the
onboarding framework has been to remove
as much friction as possible and avoid
blocking the way forward to users having
a successful start with business
Central but when getting hands on really
using a product people might run into
errors so in this release we have
improved our air handling further and
introduced actionable errors providing
an easier way for users to unblock
themselves in context at the field level
such as refreshing the page or accepting
the recommended
actions and to learn more about
actionable errors and how you as a
partner can or developer can leverage
these new
patterns you should check out the
session about uh productivity features
in the
client um and as always you can find
more documentation on Microsoft learn
and with that over to you San to tell us
what's next thank you Sarah to talking
about actions of course you have an
action now to go and uptake these
patterns uh for error handling in your
apps but so do we we also have actions
on spreading out these patterns to more
scenarios in the Bas app and our first
party
apps and talking about actions here are
some actions for you to conclude the
session if you want to build an
onboarding app you can start right away
with forking the sample app that's on
GitHub so look for onboarding sample app
for GitHub in the Microsoft repost and
you can hit the ground running and start
using that as a template to figure out
which events do I subscribe to where do
I change the banner text and so on and
start to think about how you can profile
your your website visitors you can
easily test this out for example with a
uh with sample power apps and build it
you don't have to do it on the web and
once you sort of got the hang of it on
how to produce uh what we call the
signup context and you can read more
about that in the documentation by the
way once youve got the Hang about that
then add it to your website start
profiling customers load the right
solution so that they can be matched
with what they expect to
see on the business side of things you
could also consider how you're offering
your
services we see great examples and great
success with Partners who bundle up uh
the whole onboarding implementation uh
data support licenses in one monthly
recurring Fe fee per User it's super
easy it's super easy for customers to
get to know their total cost of
ownership that way and actually seems
like a very viable business
model again check out the documentation
everything we've talked about here today
is documented here at ak. msbz
onboarding and finally maybe most
importantly for anything that you do
with customers use application insights
to track
telemetry
it's not hard to set up it's super cheap
and actually it will pay for itself if
you use it as an upsell and proactive
assistance for your customers there's a
bold statement but we actually think
there's a lot more that can be done with
Telemetry and application
insights as for other sessions Sarah
already mentioned that you should check
out the new productivity features in the
web client and what's new in Telemetry
and adding existing table fields to
optimize your pages are just great
examples and related content to the
session so go check them
out ultimately to close out if you have
a question contact us on Yammer that's
where all of us are and uh there's a
great partner Community there on Yammer
as well it's likely that if you have an
issue someone else has run into that
same issue as well so let's get the
conversation going there also join the
public conversation on Twitter or X and
if you're looking for any resources that
you can't find but you think there's a
resource out there related to business
Central chances are that they will exist
at this aka. msbc all alas here if you
think something is missing in the
product give us the idea submit it to
ak. msbz IDs and finally engage with us
in the office hours call calls on these
specific topics so check the calendar
for office hours Scrolls at ak. msbc
office hours and with that we like to
thank you for listening to this
presentation and for your attention
remember that you can check out all the
other business Central launch event
sessions on
demand thank you very
much